<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Lipen.co</title>
  <subtitle>Today I Learned</subtitle>
  <id>http://lipen.co/til</id>
  <link href="http://lipen.co/til"/>
  <link href="http://lipen.co/til/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2013-07-15T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Magdalena Lipinska</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Ninja Style</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://lipen.co/til/ninja-style.html"/>
    <id>http://lipen.co/til/ninja-style.html </id>
    <published>2013-07-15T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-07-15T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;JavaScript is becoming more domesticated. I made 6 template generators, and it really seems I can contribute to impress.js and make user&amp;#8217;s life easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had Skype call with my mentor Chris, who shared with me his golden tip: &amp;#8220;code like a Ninja&amp;#8221;. True Ninja would add one or two lines to the root code and work would be done, but Chris quickly produce and explain also more lame solution (in separate script) without even a drop of sweat sitting in hot New Jersey. I really think it was not too easy to generate slides template in the &amp;#8220;snake&amp;#8221; grid style like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;				1st slide, 2nd slide, 3rd slide, 4th slide,
				8th slide, 7th slide, 6th slide, 5th slide,
				9th slide, 10th slide, 11th slide, 12th slide...&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My &lt;a href='https://trello.com/b/Bi7XqDyM/impress-js-summer-of-code'&gt;Trello Board&lt;/a&gt; looks like a military proving ground, &lt;a href='https://github.com/lipenco/theme-impress/commit/77a454becafb577d176983b6af1eb59ca19a7fdb#commitcomment-3636545'&gt;GitHub impress repo&lt;/a&gt; like my essays form school - so many comments and corrections. If my literature teacher had had so much patience like Bartek I would definitely have become a literature teacher. Luck me, he did not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='today_i_learned'&gt;Today I Learned:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How combine functions in functions and reverse slides direction.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;How makes JavaScript understand what I want.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Small parenthesis can make you feel stupid, if you don&amp;#8217;t add them in a right place.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Nice tools like &lt;a href='http://jsbeautifier.org/'&gt;jsbeautifier&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href='http://jshint.com/'&gt;JS Hint&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Watermelon has 300 kcl for 1kg.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To sum up&lt;/em&gt;: If I think twice, I will figure it out on the fifth attempt.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Działa! (pol. it works) Hurra, Hurra!</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://lipen.co/til/dziala.html"/>
    <id>http://lipen.co/til/dziala.html </id>
    <published>2013-07-10T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-07-10T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The end of the theoretical muttering about objects and arrays came with new assignments. Though it has been difficult, step by step, I am preparing a slide position generator. This tasks seems to be as exciting as it is frustrating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first exercise sounds easy: &amp;#8220;Let&amp;#8217;s assume that the HTML for an impress.js presentation is created (all steps) but without &lt;code&gt;data-attribute&lt;/code&gt;s. So steps don&amp;#8217;t have any position defined in HTML. (..) Write a script that runs before impress.init() that adds some positions to all steps. (..).&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was jumping for happiness when my simple &lt;a href='https://github.com/lipenco/impress.js-myscript'&gt;for loop&lt;/a&gt; worked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a nice talk with my friend, an experienced developer. He tried hard to persuade me to start with Java or C#. In his opinion, JavaScript is not the right place to start: it is difficult to debug and it is hard to learn all the programming logic in the browser. &amp;#8220;The language is not important, abstract thinking and code writing are skills you need now.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am thinking seriously about getting back to the &lt;a href='https://www.edx.org/course/harvard-university/cs50x/introduction-computer-science/1022'&gt;CS50x&lt;/a&gt; computer science course from Harvard that I started a long time ago and never finished. It was just too painful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='today_i_learned'&gt;Today I Learned:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thanks to Bartek I understood that impress.js is not listening to any code I am writing outside this function, which wasn&amp;#8217;t too obvious for me.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;He taught me many other things, and found out that sometimes I pretend I understand.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;How to make a CSS hovering animated effect that doesn&amp;#8217;t go back after hovering ends. &lt;a href='http://jsfiddle.net/rHpDn/3/'&gt;Here is a nice example.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To sum up&lt;/em&gt;: Success should be celebrated.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Are We There Yet?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://lipen.co/til/are-we-there-yet.html"/>
    <id>http://lipen.co/til/are-we-there-yet.html </id>
    <published>2013-07-09T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-07-09T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;No! Why should I write my own JS code if there are so many nice books to read about it. The suspense just keep me hooked into reading more and more of them. It is a drama and the climax seems to be unreachable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://eloquentjavascript.net/'&gt;Eloquent JavaScript&lt;/a&gt; is the best position about JS I&amp;#8217;ve read so far. Not only because I can read it in Polish. I am working my ass off doing (most of) book&amp;#8217;s exercises, but let&amp;#8217;s face it - it is just not right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides I finished my two templates. I am excited about the feedback -I will get it tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The disappointing experience was my attempt to figure out how to solve the problem of &lt;a href='https://github.com/bartaz/impress.js/pull/131'&gt;relative step positioning in impress.js&lt;/a&gt;. I need to give a try again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='today_i_learned'&gt;Today I Learned:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Closures, recursion, scopes (again), looping (again), strict mode (again)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Polish words in programming sounds so surprising.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To sum up&lt;/em&gt;: Vote for &lt;a href='http://impressjs.challengepost.com/submissions/16286-presentation-about-google-convenient-tax-policy'&gt;my presentation&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>JavaScript is Eating From my Hand.</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://lipen.co/til/javascript-is-eating-from-my-hand.html"/>
    <id>http://lipen.co/til/javascript-is-eating-from-my-hand.html </id>
    <published>2013-07-06T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-07-06T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Reading JavaScript code out loud, line by line with someone who is able to correct you and explain things is 100 times more helpful than reading books and repeating theory. John said it was fun to explain impress.js to me. I felt sorry for him all these long hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took longer than expected, but I am kind of proud that I am able to translate this code into words. Still I have a feeling that the path from understanding to writing is long and bumpy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='today_i_learned'&gt;Today I Learned:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My project management is not great (yet), but I don&amp;#8217;t mind reading code in the train on Saturday. I will be ready with all my assignments for my call with Bartek on Monday.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/JavaScript/Guide'&gt;JavaScript Guide by Mozilla&lt;/a&gt; is worth reading.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I am getting this strange habit, that instead of facebooking to relax I am looking for and staring on GitHub cool open source projects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To sum up&lt;/em&gt;: &lt;a href='http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yfT-ISOwRtw'&gt;Will never be a summer like this&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Where the Magic and Panic Happen</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://lipen.co/til/where-the-magic-and-panic-happen.html"/>
    <id>http://lipen.co/til/where-the-magic-and-panic-happen.html </id>
    <published>2013-07-04T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-07-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today I touched the guts. It was my JavaScript day. I finished up the &amp;#8220;Javascript Enlighment&amp;#8221; book, but with the feeling that I still don&amp;#8217;t know anything, I sat with John to reviews some impress.js JavaScript code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After 2 hours we found ourselves on the 75th line (out of 800). Guys, this is so difficult! Stuff like &amp;#8216;use strict&amp;#8217;, &lt;a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Immediately-invoked_function_expression'&gt;IIFE&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8230; OMG! Guys, it is wild.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John is invincible: &amp;#8220;Ok, let&amp;#8217;s skip that, I will ask Bartek,&amp;#8221; I said being beaten by the code. &amp;#8220;No, I also want to to understand&amp;#8221;, his striving for knowledge made us slower, me more nervous and him more proud of his teaching skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='today_i_learned'&gt;Today I Learned:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dealing with impress.js JS code is super difficult.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Dealing with JS books are super boring and they won&amp;#8217;t teach you JS.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;You should try understand impress.js code because it is wild.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;You should take a nap every 100 lines of impress.js JS code.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Rotation of crops helps you to stay excited and not to panic: on the side I am doing my &lt;a href='http://lipen.co/til-informal-tech-education/'&gt;friend&amp;#8217;s website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To sum up&lt;/em&gt;: &amp;#8216;Certain things are false, everything else is true&amp;#8217; - &amp;#8216;JavaScript Enlightement&amp;#8217;, p. 91%.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>It Only Looks that Simple</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://lipen.co/til/it-only-seems-to-be-easy.html"/>
    <id>http://lipen.co/til/it-only-seems-to-be-easy.html </id>
    <published>2013-07-02T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-07-02T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;But is is not. &lt;a href='http://lipen.co/theme-impress/theme-index.html#/slide1'&gt;This is what I did today&lt;/a&gt; - it&amp;#8217;s a work in progress for a universal and aesthetic template for the masses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='today_i_learned'&gt;Today I Learned:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I can spend 3h choosing and adjusting images - it is kind of annoying to have too many ideas and nice pictures to choose from.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Photoshop is a terrible trap that caught me and didn&amp;#8217;t want to let me go.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The first day of &lt;a href='https://ep2013.europython.eu'&gt;EuroPython&lt;/a&gt; was rough for me - just too much Python. But at least it let me go forwrd with my impress.js &amp;#8216;assignments&amp;#8217;.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Right positioning in impress.js is kind of difficult.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To sum up&lt;/em&gt;: Limoncello does taste like a lemon soap, but it makes you feel so Florentine.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
