<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Lipen.co</title>
  <subtitle>Today I Learned</subtitle>
  <id>http://lipen.co/til</id>
  <link href="http://lipen.co/til"/>
  <link href="http://lipen.co/til/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2013-07-19T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Magdalena Lipinska</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title/>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://lipen.co/til/code-against-human-stupidity.html"/>
    <id>http://lipen.co/til/code-against-human-stupidity.html </id>
    <published>2013-07-19T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-07-19T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2 id='title_code_against_human_stupidity'&gt;title: Code Against Human Stupidity&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Solving problems without restoring to any help are probably the most rewarding moments in learning process. But just the fact it works, does not mean it is good enough. What if the user puts the argument which does not make any sense? Seems like my first idea for solution made with &lt;code&gt;console.log(&amp;quot;you are a bad programmer&amp;quot;)&lt;/code&gt; is not exactly acceptable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I&amp;#8217;ve found better one:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;distance &amp;amp;&amp;amp; distance &amp;gt; 700? distance : distance = 1000;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Bartek wanted something more readable, more simple;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;if (distance &amp;amp;&amp;amp; distance &amp;gt; 700) {
       distance;
    }
    else {
        distance = 1000;
    }&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still not sexy enough;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;if (distance &amp;amp;&amp;amp; distance &amp;gt; 700);
    else {
       distance = 1000;
    }&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shorter but not better;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;if (!(distance &amp;amp;&amp;amp; distance &amp;gt; 700)) {
       distance = 1000;
    }&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Almost eureka!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;if (!distance || distance &amp;lt; 700) {
       distance = 1000;
    }&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So simple!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My code is user-friendly look with &lt;a href='https://github.com/lipenco/impress.js-myscript'&gt;read.me on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='today_i_learned'&gt;Today I Learned:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Writing one code in 5 versions.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Thinking shorter and brighter.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I finished my &lt;a href='http://lipen.co/til-informal-tech-education/'&gt;&amp;#8220;side&amp;#8221; project&lt;/a&gt; for my portfolio. To make the SoundCloud iframe not destroy my loading time was a great challange.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To sum up&lt;/em&gt;: In 3 months I will be totally employable ;]&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>School is Deprecated</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://lipen.co/til/school-is-deprecated.html"/>
    <id>http://lipen.co/til/school-is-deprecated.html </id>
    <published>2013-07-17T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-07-17T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I decided to go back to the programing principles and practice some logic, sexy syntaxes and abstract thinking with #C. From today, every day I will spend 70 min, with very a guy from Harvard at &lt;a href='https://www.edx.org/course/harvard-university/cs50x/introduction-computer-science/1022'&gt;CS50 Course&lt;/a&gt;. It is online, it is free, it has a massive number of cool features, among others, it provides you with build in console for coding in #C.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.edx.org/'&gt;Edx.org&lt;/a&gt; is full of courses I want to do as well, but first thing first. With online resorces like this it&amp;#8217;s just clear that traditional school is deprecated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My impress.js generators looks more and more professional. The user can now invoke the function with creates an automated layout with changeable parameters like distance between slides or radius when it comes to circle layouts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out some of my 10 layout generations: &lt;a href='http://lipen.co/impress.js-myscript/index-circle-v2.html#/step-1'&gt;circle layout&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href='http://lipen.co/impress.js-myscript/index-snake-grid.html#/step-11'&gt;grid&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='today_i_learned'&gt;Today I Learned:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to be a role model RGSoC participant and I signed up for IRC discussions.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;How to create invokable functions with changeable parameters.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Principles of cryptography.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Going through all daily newsletters about web design and JavaScript takes too long.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To sum up&lt;/em&gt;: Yes, I deserved your Kudo :)&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Ninja Style</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://lipen.co/til/ninja-style.html"/>
    <id>http://lipen.co/til/ninja-style.html </id>
    <published>2013-07-15T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-07-15T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;JavaScript is becoming more domesticated. I made 6 template generators, and it really seems I can contribute to impress.js and make the user&amp;#8217;s life easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had Skype a call with my mentor Chris, who shared with me his golden tip: &amp;#8220;code like a Ninja.&amp;#8221; It means to add as little code as possible to do all the magic. It was not possible this time, as we couldn&amp;#8217;t code inside core impress.js file, but Chris quickly explained and figured out the solution without a drop of sweat. I really think it was not too easy to generate a slide template in the &amp;#8220;snake&amp;#8221; grid style like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;				1st slide, 2nd slide, 3rd slide, 4th slide,
				8th slide, 7th slide, 6th slide, 5th slide,
				9th slide, 10th slide, 11th slide, 12th slide...&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My &lt;a href='https://trello.com/b/Bi7XqDyM/impress-js-summer-of-code'&gt;Trello Board&lt;/a&gt; looks like a military proving ground, my fork of &lt;a href='https://github.com/lipenco/theme-impress/commit/77a454becafb577d176983b6af1eb59ca19a7fdb#commitcomment-3636545'&gt;impress&lt;/a&gt; like my essays form school - so many comments and corrections. If my literature teacher had had so much patience for me like Bartek I would definitely have become a literature teacher. Luck me, he was impatient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='today_i_learned'&gt;Today I Learned:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to use nested loops to reverse slides direction.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;How to make JavaScript understand what I want.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Small parenthesis can make you feel stupid, if you don&amp;#8217;t add them in the right place.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Nice tools like &lt;a href='http://jsbeautifier.org/'&gt;jsbeautifier&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href='http://jshint.com/'&gt;JS Hint&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Watermelon has 300 kcal for 1kg.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To sum up&lt;/em&gt;: If I think twice, I will figure it out on the fifth attempt.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Działa! (pol. it works) Hurra, Hurra!</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://lipen.co/til/dziala.html"/>
    <id>http://lipen.co/til/dziala.html </id>
    <published>2013-07-10T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-07-10T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The end of the theoretical muttering about objects and arrays came with new assignments. Though it has been difficult, step by step, I am preparing a slide position generator. This tasks seems to be as exciting as it is frustrating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first exercise sounds easy: &amp;#8220;Let&amp;#8217;s assume that the HTML for an impress.js presentation is created (all steps) but without &lt;code&gt;data-attribute&lt;/code&gt;s. So steps don&amp;#8217;t have any position defined in HTML. (..) Write a script that runs before impress.init() that adds some positions to all steps. (..).&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was jumping for happiness when my simple &lt;a href='https://github.com/lipenco/impress.js-myscript'&gt;for loop&lt;/a&gt; worked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a nice talk with my friend, an experienced developer. He tried hard to persuade me to start with Java or C#. In his opinion, JavaScript is not the right place to start: it is difficult to debug and it is hard to learn all the programming logic in the browser. &amp;#8220;The language is not important, abstract thinking and code writing are skills you need now.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am thinking seriously about getting back to the &lt;a href='https://www.edx.org/course/harvard-university/cs50x/introduction-computer-science/1022'&gt;CS50x&lt;/a&gt; computer science course from Harvard that I started a long time ago and never finished. It was just too painful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='today_i_learned'&gt;Today I Learned:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thanks to Bartek I understood that impress.js is not listening to any code I am writing outside this function, which wasn&amp;#8217;t too obvious for me.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;He taught me many other things, and found out that sometimes I pretend I understand.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;How to make a CSS hovering animated effect that doesn&amp;#8217;t go back after hovering ends. &lt;a href='http://jsfiddle.net/rHpDn/3/'&gt;Here is a nice example.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To sum up&lt;/em&gt;: Success should be celebrated.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Are We There Yet?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://lipen.co/til/are-we-there-yet.html"/>
    <id>http://lipen.co/til/are-we-there-yet.html </id>
    <published>2013-07-09T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-07-09T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;No! Why should I write my own JS code if there are so many nice books to read about it. The suspense just keep me hooked into reading more and more of them. It is a drama and the climax seems to be unreachable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://eloquentjavascript.net/'&gt;Eloquent JavaScript&lt;/a&gt; is the best position about JS I&amp;#8217;ve read so far. Not only because I can read it in Polish. I am working my ass off doing (most of) book&amp;#8217;s exercises, but let&amp;#8217;s face it - it is just not right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides I finished my two templates. I am excited about the feedback -I will get it tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The disappointing experience was my attempt to figure out how to solve the problem of &lt;a href='https://github.com/bartaz/impress.js/pull/131'&gt;relative step positioning in impress.js&lt;/a&gt;. I need to give a try again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='today_i_learned'&gt;Today I Learned:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Closures, recursion, scopes (again), looping (again), strict mode (again)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Polish words in programming sounds so surprising.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To sum up&lt;/em&gt;: Vote for &lt;a href='http://impressjs.challengepost.com/submissions/16286-presentation-about-google-convenient-tax-policy'&gt;my presentation&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>JavaScript is Eating From my Hand.</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://lipen.co/til/javascript-is-eating-from-my-hand.html"/>
    <id>http://lipen.co/til/javascript-is-eating-from-my-hand.html </id>
    <published>2013-07-06T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-07-06T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Reading JavaScript code out loud, line by line with someone who is able to correct you and explain things is 100 times more helpful than reading books and repeating theory. John said it was fun to explain impress.js to me. I felt sorry for him all these long hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took longer than expected, but I am kind of proud that I am able to translate this code into words. Still I have a feeling that the path from understanding to writing is long and bumpy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='today_i_learned'&gt;Today I Learned:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My project management is not great (yet), but I don&amp;#8217;t mind reading code in the train on Saturday. I will be ready with all my assignments for my call with Bartek on Monday.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/JavaScript/Guide'&gt;JavaScript Guide by Mozilla&lt;/a&gt; is worth reading.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I am getting this strange habit, that instead of facebooking to relax I am looking for and staring on GitHub cool open source projects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To sum up&lt;/em&gt;: &lt;a href='http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yfT-ISOwRtw'&gt;Will never be a summer like this&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
