<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2013-06-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Rails, impress.js, Design &amp; Desapintment.</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/beeing -offered.html"/>
    <id>/beeing -offered.html</id>
    <published>2013-06-20T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-06-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’ll give you $10 if I can get this application work on my computer. Additional features like air conditioning highly desirable. You in?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After productive couple of hours with Bettina and Maren (members of the Ruby Monsters team form Berlin) and working together on implementation of my classy design for rails application we apparently had some achievements. Though, ff it hadn’t been for John’s help we would have made just a big mess in the code. It’s too bad that when I tried to run application on my own computer it didn’t work. Problems with database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had to skip working on design implementation and wait for more patience to solve this problem. Instead I put my hands into &lt;a href='https://github.com/bartaz/impress.js/'&gt;impress.js&lt;/a&gt; – the open source project I will work on with Bartek (impress.js’ owner and my coaches- John, Chris and Tom). To understand what is going on behind the scenes, or canvas in this case I read the documentation and went through jquery code. My jquery skill can be compared to my Spanish skills – I understand to certain extend, but the active usage is quite miserable. I think i have to focus more on this language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://github.com/bartaz/impress.js/'&gt;impress.js&lt;/a&gt; has now it’s challenge on &lt;a href='http://impressjs.challengepost.com/'&gt;ChallengePost&lt;/a&gt;. It is a great opportunity to practice a little before the Summer of Code. I am building my presentation about tax evasion trying to add extended features. I already got to some very fancy css3 effects, but I guess the art of this challenge is to translate this big css code into jquery and make using the features universal and simple. I will try hard, but am not too optimistic about my ability to do it at this point. With java script or without – I will promise to gift your eyes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='i_learned_today'&gt;I learned today:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A good chank of CSS animations and 3D translations effects&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;How to create sub-steps - showing hidden content without changing the slide with a delay CSS property.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I started to believe I have to errase my computer to get this database to work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To sum up: Steve Jobs would have checked out much sooner had he known this was the way I could set up my developer’s tools.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Blast Off</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/blast-off.html"/>
    <id>/blast-off.html</id>
    <published>2013-06-19T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-06-19T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Time to prepare for the Rails Girls Summer of Code. My first task was to create this blog to track my work. It seems like changing my every-day passion into a full-time routine, but as an ex-journalist I&amp;#8217;m looking forward to some exhibitionist pleasure. It&amp;#8217;s most likely a one-sided pleasure, my dear small audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rails Girls Summer of Code starts in two weeks. All the participants are supposed to keep a blog to track progress. I&amp;#8217;ve seen some of them already – beautiful design made in five minutes using popular services. Some people call it effectiveness, but there is such a masochistic pleasure in reinventing the wheel that I can&amp;#8217;t resist. I decided to build my hand-made blog. John believes that the only sensible choice for a developer blog is to use a static website generator. I am under constant static-website propaganda that I started to believe that a good front-end developer does not need to get her hands dirty with PHP and I gave up tha idea of creating a Wordpress theme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://middlemanapp.com'&gt;Middleman&lt;/a&gt;, the open static website generator made it possible to build all all the blogging infrastructure on my website. I hit a roadblock when I decided to add a &lt;a href='https://github.com/masukomi/kudos'&gt;Kudos&lt;/a&gt; feature to my posts. Kudos are definitely too &amp;#8220;osom&amp;#8221; (pol. awesome) to go without. This feature totally made my day, and by made my day I mean it just took all the time. Not only mine, but also John&amp;#8217;s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;jQuery was not enough for building Kudos. We needed a backend to store our Kudos and remember the huge numbers of Kudos you all are going to give me. Since there&amp;#8217;s no way to dyanmically store data on a static website, we had to use something else. &lt;a href='http://parse.com'&gt;Parse&lt;/a&gt; to the rescue. After painfully wading through the documentation and trying hundreds of variations of code, we made it. Ok, no-cheating -he made it, I gave up on the back end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='today_i_learned'&gt;Today I Learned:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Looking at someone coding can be more tiring than coding on your own.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Before I show any code to John I have to count and correct my messy code, we will not move forward until it&amp;#8217;s cleaned up.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Learning by watching doesn&amp;#8217;t work, but it sure does speed up your progress.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To sum up&lt;/em&gt;: You&amp;#8217;d better make good use of Kudos - it cost me so much time! Viciously I (we) made it so that you cannot remove your kudo in case you change your mind ;p.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>First Post</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/first-post.html"/>
    <id>/first-post.html</id>
    <published>2013-06-18T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-06-18T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;puts &amp;quot;hello world&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
